Divya Kalaivanan

Personal Details



Divya Kalaivanan



divyakalaivanan@gmail.com



+919035470354



Bangalore, India

Skills

- Product Owner
- CAD Designer
- Project Manager
- Technical Writing
- Continuous Engineering Solutions
- International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) standards – LV Capacitor

Publication

"Finite Element Analysis of Low-velocity Impact Damage Tolerance on Composite Laminates", International Journal of Material Science.

ISSN 0973-4589 Vol 4,

Number 2(2009), pp. 101 - 114

Languages

English, Tamil, Hindi, Kannada

Hobbies

Cooking

Travelling

Profile

An incisive professional with over 11+ years of experience as Mechanical Design Engineer. Worked as part of Engineering R & D team as Senior Electromechanical Design Engineer in new product development and continuous engineering. Exposure in modeling plastics and sheet metal modules with CAD tools. Worked in a service and manufacturing sectors with global clients and cross functional teams respectively.

Employment

Schneider Electric, Bangalore, India

Jul 2014 – Jan 2021

Senior Electromechanical Design Engineer - Engineering - R&D Team

- New Design and Validation of:
 - Product Terminal Covers considering IP 20, Ventilation and Aesthetic aspects for key reference.
 - Impacted mechanical components in product during new reference development from 3Phase to 1Phase product design.
- Gained knowledge and experience in design and testing standards of LV Capacitor as per International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC - 80631) standards.
- Worked as a Technical Lead and Project Owner for enormous projects, which
 involved handling projects from kick-off phase to execution and closure
 (Waterfall and Agile methodologies). Involved in scheduling, project cost
 estimation, resource calculation, etc.
- Worked with the industrialization team to validate and update required manufacturing design change for a new tool development project, targeting 35 mechanical components, without stopping the production line.
- Handled validation and product certification for UL by converting all non-UL components to UL and implementing inline monitoring the ramp-down and ramp-up of stocks for each component.
- Co-ordinated with Marketing for Literature review and translated Product Manuals and Catalogues in 7 global languages. Validated the same with respective country marketing leads.
- CQCS for any new component development and for legacy component update in-progress.
- Existing product or for new component development impact with respect to Tolerance Stack-up analysis or DFMEA or PQCS reviewed and updated.
- Continuous Engineering product feasibility with regard to both electrical and mechanical components in progress.

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore, India

Jan 2010 - Jul 2014

Project Engineer - Mechanical Design Services

- Design and validation of:
 - Metal new works TV recessed frame for single gang and mounting bracket along with Plastic Cover for the commercial market.
 - Old box to be accommodated into existing TV1 and TV3 recessed box.
 Prototyping and pre-compliance test for new old workbox.
- Worked extensively for New Product Development (NPD) for the Design of sheet metal and plastic components.
- Experience in working with Product Database Management (PDM) like EPDM,
 Windchill etc.
- Exposure in projects related to cost estimation of part and assembly, Engineering change requests and incorporating the changes in the drawings, release of the process for the parts and assembly.
- As per the technical document, various activities for Design development like product understanding, market requirements and Benchmarking were carried upon.



CAD - Certification

Certified as "Certified Solid Works Associate (CSWA)", from Best Engineering Aids & Consultancies Pvt. Ltd. (BEACON) using Solid Works 2015.

Significant Role – Schneider Electric

- **President** of Internal Compliance Committee (ICC) – "Sexual Harassment of Woman at Workplace for around a year".
- **Member** of Internal Compliance Committee (ICC) – "Sexual Harassment of Woman at Workplace for 6 years".

- Product Requirement Specifications prepared with the help of market survey and considering market
- Organized meetings to interact with clients, onsite coordinator and vendors in the USA for product understanding and prototype reviewing.
- Various concepts were proposed for the economical manufacturing process by maintaining simple manufacturing operations.
- Visited Manufacturing and Testing Units for approval of the testing execution phases and prototypes
- To convert the input files which were in pdf and .dxf format to solid works drawing files.
- The Parasolid parts and STP files had to be modelled using Solid works part modelling and create a drawing as per Client standards.
- Assembly and Drawing creation using configurations.

CAD Software skills & PDM

Company	CAD Tool	Module	PDM
Wipro Technologies	Solid Works 2013	Sheet Metal	EPDM Windchill
	Pro-E Wildfire 4	Plastic	
Schneider Electric	Pro-E Creo 2.0	Plastic & Sheet Metal	Symphony & NexGen Technology (Wave – 1)
	AutoCAD	Product labels	
	Open Project – For Project Scheduling		

Acheivements

- Awarded a certificate from Product Engineering Services (Wipro) for "Delivering the projects allocated as per commitment with quality".
- Awarded a certificate from Product Engineering Services (Wipro) for receiving "7/7 in Customer satisfaction rating for quality".
- Awarded a certificate from Product Engineering Services (Wipro) for "Delivering the projects allocated within the delivery time".
- Received "Passionate" award from Learning and development team (Schneider Electric) for showing interest towards learning and demonstrating to colleagues.
- Received "Effective" award from R&D support team for learning and validating new PDM (NextGEN), also for sharing with the team.
- Received "Effective" award from Schneider Electric for delivering projects as per commitment with quality.

Education

MTech - Manufacturing Management Jul 2018 – Sep 2020

BITS Palani, India

BTech - Production Engineering Jul 2005 – Aug 2009

National Institute of Technology (NIT), Trichy, India

12th Standard – Pre-University Board Jun 2003 – May 2005

Baldwin Women's Methodist College, Bangalore, India

10th Standard – ICSE Board May 2003

Bangalore Public School, Bangalore, India